Sagar Randive

Developer II-Software Engineering

https://www.linkedin.com/in/sagar-randive-778b50240

Enthusiastic and self-motivated Front End Developer with 4.5+ years of IT development experience working in a scrum based delivery environment. Core areas of skills are in Front End Development that includes experience in development and maintenance of Web Applications using HTML5, CSS3, ReactJS, Redux, GraphQL, JEST, React Testing Library, RTK Query, Typescript, jQuery, Javascript, Bootstrap. Excellent capability to explore learn and understand newer business domains and technology. Strong debugging and problem-solving skills with excellent understanding of development methodologies, techniques and tools. Manage team and working with large team as well as independently on different modules. Highly committed individual with proven ability to learn fast.

Experience

Developer II-Software Engineering

May 2023 - Present

UST Product Engineering

- Worked with one of the client Deluxe, It has own application offering Remote Deposit Capture (RDC) functionality to customers and financial institution.
- Worked on maintenance and improvement of Web Application (Capture Deposit, Capture Payment) for Deluxe US client using latest technology of React, context API, Typescript, JEST.
- · Worked for one of the best US client Albertsons, which is one of the largest food and drug retailers in the United States.
- Added new feature and improve the performance of item creation product as per requirement of Albertsons client using technology React, Redux, GraphQL, RTK Query, Typescript, JEST.
- Worked together with Backend, QA team and always give 100% to deliver end to end requirement to the client.
- I have experience in UI and Web development of Banking and E-commerce application.

Front End Developer

Nov 2019 - May 2023

Tata Consultancy Services

- Worked with TCS-ION project on UI Development of Digital Learning Hub, Digital Job Portal, Digital Institution Dashboard with use of React, Redux, JEST, jQuery, Javascript, Typescript Bootstrap technology.
- Responsible for development of UI from scratch and converting static UI into Dynamic web application by giving proper logic and functionality.
- Responsible for giving new efficient idea and adding new features to existing web application.
- · Worked individually or as team for developing various job modules from scratch like Create-Job, Corporate-Dashboard, Job-Dashboard, Interviewer and Learner Dashboard.
- For modules of institution dashboard developed frontend as well backend code with proper logic and functionality.
- · Acquired new technology and skills to improve productivity of project and I have experience in giving knowledge training session to the team.
- I have 3+ years of experience in maintenance and development of E-Learning and Employment application.

Technical Experience

Web Technologies & Languages:-

HTML5, CSS3, ReactJS, Redux, Typescript, GraphQL, RTK Query, JEST, React Testing Library, Styled Component, Tailwind CSS, Javascript(ES2020), Jquery, NextJS, JAVA, C, SQL.

Tools Used:

Tortoise SVN, Git, Github, Jira, Notepad++, Chrome developer tools, DevPlus, Visual Studio Code, React Developer tools, Redux Devtool, Apollo Sandbox, Copilot, Eclipse, Jenkins.

Domains:

eLearning, Banking, E-commerce

Skill

- Good numerical ability
- Coding
- Hardworking
- Continuity in work

- Problem-solving
- Time Management
- Self-motivation

Education

High School 2014-2015

- Kolhapur Divisional Board Sangli Highschool & Jr. college, Sangli.
- Aggregate(%): 74.92
- Bachelor of Engineering (Mechanical Engineering)

2015-2019

- Shivaji University P.V.P.I.T. Budhgaon.
- Aggregate(%): 64.40

Achievements

- Service and Commitment Award from Tata Consultancy Services in recognition of 3 years of dedicated service.
- Get Pat on the Back Appreciation from UST Product Engineering for delivery of critical and new feature stories in given timeline.

Personal Information

Date of Birth: January 10, 1996 Languages known: English, Hindi, Marathi.

Nationality: Indian Address: A/P: Vasagade; Tal: Palus; Dist: sangli.

Hobbies: Singing, Dancing, Standup Comedy, Workout, Tracking, Reading Story Books.